<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Feral Science</string>
    <string name="dovn_text">© Feral Science</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="yes_correct">Yes, correct!</string>
    <string name="sorry_but_you_lost_ntry_again_or_exit">Sorry but you lost... \nTry again or exit?</string>
    <string name="loading">Loading...</string>
    <string name="quizzz_rulles">Science may be as old as the human species,[3] and some of the earliest archeological evidence for scientific reasoning is tens of thousands of years old.[4] The earliest written records in the history of science come from Ancient Egypt and Mesopotamia in around 3000 to 1200 BCE.[5][6] Their contributions to mathematics, astronomy, and medicine entered and shaped Greek natural philosophy of classical antiquity, whereby formal attempts were made to provide explanations of events in the physical world based on natural causes.\n\n After the fall of the Western Roman Empire, knowledge of Greek conceptions of the world deteriorated in Western Europe during the early centuries (400 to 1000 CE) of the Middle Ages,[7] but was preserved in the Muslim world during the Islamic Golden Age[8] and later by the efforts of Byzantine Greek scholars who brought Greek manuscripts from the dying Byzantine Empire to Westerm Europe in the Renaissance.\n\nNew knowledge in science is advanced by research from scientists who are motivated by curiosity about the world and a desire to solve problems.[28][29] Contemporary scientific research is highly collaborative and is usually done by teams in academic and research institutions,[30] government agencies, and companies.[31][32] The practical impact of their work has led to the emergence of science policies that seek to influence the scientific enterprise by prioritizing the ethical and moral development of commercial products, armaments, health care, public infrastructure, and environmental protection.\nIn the sixteenth century, Nicolaus Copernicus formulated a heliocentric model of the Solar System, stating that the planets revolve around the Sun, instead of the geocentric model where the planets and the Sun revolve around the Earth. This was based on a theorem that the orbital periods of the planets are longer as their orbs are farther from the center of motion, which he found not to agree with Ptolemys model.\nAt the start of the Age of Enlightenment, Isaac Newton formed the foundation of classical mechanics by his Philosophiæ Naturalis Principia Mathematica, greatly influencing future physicists.[90] Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz incorporated terms from Aristotelian physics, now used in a new non-teleological way. This implied a shift in the view of objects: objects were now considered as having no innate goals. Leibniz assumed that different types of things all work according to the same general laws of nature, with no special formal or final causes.\nEarly in the 19th century, John Dalton suggested the modern atomic theory, based on Democritus original idea of indivisible particles called atoms.[109] The laws of conservation of energy, conservation of momentum and conservation of mass suggested a highly stable universe where there could be little loss of resources. However, with the advent of the steam engine and the industrial revolution there was an increased understanding that not all forms of energy have the same energy qualities, the ease of conversion to useful work or to another form of energy.[110] This realization led to the development of the laws of thermodynamics, in which the free energy of the universe is seen as constantly declining: the entropy of a closed universe increases over time.</string>
    <string name="about_settings">In the first half of the century, the development of antibiotics and artificial fertilizers improved human living standards globally.[116][117] Harmful environmental issues such as ozone depletion, ocean acidification, eutrophication and climate change came to the publics attention and caused the onset of environmental studies.\nThe century saw fundamental changes within science disciplines. Evolution became a unified theory in the early 20th-century when the modern synthesis reconciled Darwinian evolution with classical genetics.\nThe Human Genome Project was completed in 2003 by identifying and mapping all of the genes of the human genome.[130] The first induced pluripotent human stem cells were made in 2006, allowing adult cells to be transformed into stem cells and turn to any cell type found in the body.[131] With the affirmation of the Higgs boson discovery in 2013, the last particle predicted by the Standard Model of particle physics was found.[132] In 2015, gravitational waves, predicted by general relativity a century before, were first observed.[133][134] In 2019, the international collaboration Event Horizon Telescope presented the first direct image of a black holes accretion disk.\nSocial science is the study of human behavior and functioning of societies.[17][18] It has many disciplines that include, but are not limited to anthropology, economics, history, human geography, political science, psychology, and sociology.[17] In the social sciences, there are many competing theoretical perspectives, many of which are extended through competing research programs such as the functionalists, conflict theorists, and interactionists in sociology.[17] Due to the limitations of conducting controlled experiments involving large groups of individuals or complex situations, social scientists may adopt other research methods such as the historical method, case studies, and cross-cultural studies. Moreover, if quantitative information is available, social scientists may rely on statistical approaches to better understand social relationships and processes.\nScientific research involves using the scientific method, which seeks to objectively explain the events of nature in a reproducible way.[167] Scientists usually take for granted a set of basic assumptions that are needed to justify the scientific method: there is an objective reality shared by all rational observers; this objective reality is governed by natural laws; these laws were discovered by means of systematic observation and experimentation.[168] Mathematics is essential in the formation of hypotheses, theories, and laws, because it is used extensively in quantitative modeling, observing, and collecting measurements.[169] Statistics is used to summarize and analyze data, which allows scientists to assess the reliability of experimental results.\nScientific research is published in a range of literature.[183] Scientific journals communicate and document the results of research carried out in universities and various other research institutions, serving as an archival record of science. The first scientific journal, Journal des sçavans by Philosophical Transactions, began publication in 1665. Since that time the total number of active periodicals has steadily increased. In 1981, one estimate for the number of scientific and technical journals in publication was 11,500.</string>
</resources>